OLEG NOSYREV

Front-End Engineer

Seattle. WA 98109 ymmy1.github.io/

(425)625-1273 github.com/ymmy1

oleg.ymmy@gmail.com in linkedin.com/in/oleg-nosyrev

SUMMARY

Self-taught Front End Developer with 4+ of professional and 9+ years of personal development experience as well as an Associate's Degree holder in Culinary Arts and world-class achievements in Gymnastics as a gymnast and a coach. Attention-to-detail-focused, organized, a quick learner, a great communicator and overall a friendly team member.

SKILLS

React. is (LinkedIntop 20%), JavaScript (LinkedIntop 15%), HTML (LinkedIntop 15%), CSS (LinkedIntop 5%), SASS/SCSS, Tailwind Vue.js, TypeScript and click for more.

EXPERIENCE

ITENTIAL

Software Engineer - Front End | November 2021 - May 2023 | Atlanta, GA (Remote)

- Responsible for 2 applications used directly by Fortune 500 network engineers.
- Improved application 1's load speed by 45%.
- Reduced the number of bug tickets at the start by 90%.
- Planned and architected the application 2 from zero.
- Led a team of 4 front-end developers in the application 2.
- Technologies used throughout the development: React, Emotion, SCSS, JavaScript and TypeScript.

MINORITY PROGRAMMERS' ASSOCIATION (MPA)

Front-End Engineer (Contract) | April 2021 - August 2021 | Washington D.C. (Remote)

 A startup contract was to develop a mentor-mentee matching frontend for this project and more. (React.js, Tailwind)

ALPHA GYMNASTICS

Front-End Developer / Website Content Manager | November 2018 - December 2021 | Woodinville, WA

 Re-built and later managed a business website's frontend that multiplied the volume of new customers to the gym by more than 300%. (HTML, CSS, JavaScript)

EDUCATION

HARVARD UNIVERSITY | Certificate in Web Development with Python and JavaScript Graduated November 2020 | Cambridge, MA

HARVARD UNIVERSITY | Certificate in Computer Science 50

Graduated June 2020 | Cambridge, MA

UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON | Certificate in Front-End Web Development Graduated August 2019 | Seattle, WA

VISAGINAS CITY COLLEGE | Associate's Degree in Culinary Arts & Chef Training Graduated June 2015 | Visaginas, Lithuania

LANGUAGES

English, Russian, Lithuanian.